Cool get started.
Welcome build day one...it's been pretty cool
dasi so far surprise actually by how much people showed up I moved to the five
...pm slot and you guys are troopers appreciate that thanks for joining today in the session
we talking about building applications with the microsoft as your marketplace.
...objectives aren't you guys take...or subjects...when you do during the session is learn
with the microsoft...marketplaces build cool services an application is easy
and fun and productive and take ways are that you can build cloud
skill services really easily you build...any language any platform although I won't be doing it
...language...platform today you can try to...marketplace
two-day for free if you have already taken advantage of atrophy trial.
...you...actually sell your services fairly seriously imagine marketplace.
So, what about...little bit about me before it started I'm chris I'm appealing to measure I work
in...organ billing now I work measure marketplace recently got married my wife
Thank you she keeps me together.
And, then another...you go there this is to is a lot of food.
If you competitive eater...fact about me this is five pounds of pancakes eight
and ten minutes obviously quit that and work for microsoft now and,...to say
I quite like blueberry pancakes anymore but,...right into...so ice-breaker so,
what is microsoft asher marketplace a lot of you might think,
you know, the...is...there's a mobile store a windows store and agile
marketplace...confusing we're doing a big effort to make a lot of consolidation of what this
is microsoft as a marketplace is an online marketplace
to discover the purchase provision integrated services and applications that
...extend cashmere?
So, it's an ecosystem.
Why using microsoft measure marketplace
it's a growing ecosystem we have I as we have paths we...the first
price services third-party services we're trying to constantly fill gaps...trying to figure out from
...what kind of services they actually want to build on to create really awesome solutions
for customers or even internally with their own companies?
It's a one-stop-shop so as I said before a lot of folks novel many
storefronts fragile...to consolidate all that make everything go through
one-point-one point of contact one storefront so you're not going to multiple stores
...certain things and everything feels familiar inconsistent.
Then we also are focusing a lot on
...you why and making the back and actually integrate easily so when you purchases services was
first party third-party of across a stack they'll integrate very easily together
and seamlessly a lot of corners take the initiative to make it so it's plug-and-play ready.
And, then finally there's one...address subscription has one bill you're going to our marketplace
you can purchase any service you want without one you don't have to
re-enter credit cards you don't have to have anything other than worrying about what that services that you want to do.
Another point...using marketplaces we have a global reach so right now and
...in eighty-six countries that means we can sell to a six different countries
and see there's a long list of them here potentially are not from united states you might
...country on here and this is growing...both from a cell...and
...from perspective
so we can sell to certain regions and we can sell your products from certain regions.
But, the point here is that we have a very large global outreach so getting your
services in here is really great for marketing and for your global marketplace?
So, how does...up microsoft as...was work?
Well, first we have free tears and free trials that means you get the try things before you buy them
that's great there's no commitment is very flexible subscription options so
...you can try you pretty much pay for you use or some partners even allow you to
...their service for free and use it for a month so,
that there are moves a lot of friction...to understand how powerful the ecosystem is in the services within
...microsoft measure and again...on...on this one...payment instrument
measure so makes it very seamless you really have to worry about just the core competency which is
finding the service building with the service and creating solutions for your customers.
And, then there's large work force behind you microsoft provides all of building assistance as well as microsoft
and our partners are providers provide a product support.
What's for sale.
Have lots of things for...and this is also growing...part of growing ecosystem web analytics
monitoring where development tools data in storage
...back-up media web list goes on
...identity access management the idea is that we sell these tools
via different kind of deploy mechanisms summer vietnam's
summer web services summer mobile it's across many platforms
...in many languages we try to be platform agnostic so that we can
sport all customers and rand-r partners?
Now the part that is...be most of this demo is going to be a show-and-tell so
during this presentation...building an application using lots of services in the microsoft
measure marketplace it's going to be kind of like a child age game memory if you remember that it's
cards are...you flip them over...try to find all the matches once you
complete it you've completed the game where you've...build a basic memory app.
...going to add a leader board to it so that way you can actually play the game over and over again
aggregate your score as well as rank yourself across other players in the system.
They're going to have you invite friends via email service.
Or...you want to play or...more dynamic...let the user choose the top of
...game using some of our bing search and being image api is.
Format international chat some to be verbose it's going to spanish and english but it can show that
they'll be a chat room with the memory game with the leader board and you can chat in
different languages.
And, finally...the...play.
So, let's switch over.
And, before...the demo I'm going to show you the microsoft measure portal.
That portal dot...dot
...you guys and see if you can't just let me know and...resume and more.
You can customize the start
...we call this and that has all these parts are important use you can imagine like a
...you have a lot of parts that would be pinned here that are important for the
...healthier services other integrated how the...many open these
...actually shows you what you want to do I can change the theme.
So, it's pretty diverse and how the
...works but, I'm going to...marketplace?
And, here we have a high-level categories...show you a lot of services I mentioned before the...buckets the
first thing where do is going to use measure website or web app you openness
...details played tells you...it is shows you kind of what it looks like when you have a
deployed that has a lot of links...kinda learn about the augmentation for tutorials
...all that kind of stuff...going to...is we're not deploy website here to...empty website and
...visual studio and...website deploy to this website so,
you can see kind-of...you can do is both from and id...and from the portal?
Sauna call memory.
With friends demo.
I've already created a app service plan no I haven't so I will create a new one or
I'll just use this one you can see comes of the website which is a free...so it's not
must perform website but it's free...great for a demo it'll be in the west us
are actually less create a new one...san-francisco today.
That's called apps service.
I'm not sure where this is not working may have to keep clicking there we go
we can see all the pricing there's lots of pricing I'm...not going to a very large ones
and qubit small...pry to the free again.
...choose a resource group which is associate with my subscription payment id which I
talked about earlier this is group one which is in with us and I will choose a location
deploy this website...us so let's...we have a lot of customers are all of us
...plate we want to have the best performance credit here.
While this is creating it doesn't take more than a few...actually do that I'm also going to use
...sql vm as my back...store stuff for my website all use
...search here so you can see...action for this is sql twenty-eight
...the reason one...of like twenty...
Because it's much cheaper for demo purpose.
Same process.
...host name.
We go we'll call
...vm host for game.
No, way that's already taken.
What is called memory?
Great...the same as my actual.
Account.
Ago...you can see the website just completely on the left I got a success that
...actually easy store one.
It's hard to lean over and type on this thing.
I'm not going to do twelve that would be fairly expensive for me so I will choose to view all
of these and...choose more formal plan for me.
Again, this is send...you can do you can choose basic tears and try things and you can always
scale-up or down to don't plan and then you can also...services depending on load networks
...well as for websites I...a for hundred-million choose that.
Not a new additional can fake I'm going to co-located the resource group
measure has this concept of resource group which is a container all your services will resides
that way when you do service for their operations sales...share the same
lifecycle.
Such a way to organize all your services
...large corporations or even a small company has multiple types of applications they want
organizing separately.
Yeah, later on I'll actually go through the part where
people can onboard and there's different operations you can do based on how you want to display things
...wanna-be of gm versus a website or web app you can choose pricing
models it's fairly flexible and it's changing as we get more and more people in our system to
learn more about how people are selling to their customers quick question.
I will go to the west us I...see to...question feel free to interrupt.
So, this actually takes fifteen minutes to create being use fairly easy to create I
created one of here already and I have that actually on the website so what I want
...now is I have this website up...go-to into...to this...show you that it's an empty website.
And, I'll just have all the
...plates of the says hey you've done it correctly here's some resources get started.
So, close that.
This is actually call resource level blade so for any resource regardless if it's a website of
...a database it will look and feel the same way
...be commands the top for managing it usually have some essentials...which tells you a lot of
information about that you have a quick start you can do ad which is active,
active directory for this you can tag it so we can do things for billing
...more containers organization
there's lots of dashboard information which is specific to the service down here which shows you status of
it running how much usage you've done quotas scaling lots of stuff
...specific to the service a lot of it's free and...out-of-the-box which is great so in a
minimizes and open up my project I've already prebuilt the basic game which is...six
card memory game what I do a show you how actually created it from scratch since we
...sixty-minutes I have to do it fairly quickly that's why I'm pretty
bacon's and things so if I go to visual studio I'm going to see sharpening choose web
...an empty sp dot net website?
And, give...name are not can actually create this one you can add application insights by default
...analytics monitoring for this so if there's ways you want to enhance performance or find out if you're
doing better with your customers see how the loads doing...website application insights as a great addition.
...here...choose nbc...model for our website.
You can change authentication for ours we're just going to individual user counts so-if you-can
log n to the user we can see the leader board and chat everyone's...unique identity you
can deploy actually from...so you can has...cloud and notice you can do on a website or vm so this is all
...compute stack I'm not going to do this right now because I've already pre baked it
...back out here and I will...the project whoops.
...open that again I apologize.
nbc if enough monetize model you controller you have a model which is the data and the and the
logic...do over this data you have a view which is what the...see when I go to your website
never controller which more or less controls all the data and interactions tune from that view it's a
great way...dynamically have a view and the reason why we're using that is because in our game...
playing a game as me things that are pulling on the cider happening you want to refresher game the
...really...way around that so we're going to start in every phases project from the top-down
...view will go usually to the controller and we'll go to the model
...that you can cnn my index the html or cs html.
This is more or less just how the view looks so there's a header
which says hello we'll say hello to whoever the user is logged in
will have authentication for the easy game so they won't say anything other than hello we have
some dave's and each dev...zero to sixteen because we...all this...six card game
two-sixteen card game they have cars that are flip down.
And, each card has a unique image too it's just a little...to it and,
these digital actually based on user interaction will flip will hide
one hyde it's more or less our view of the actual memory card game for this demo.
Then for this you can see...and I have
...sorry about that means zoom in you can see we have some functions.
When the home pages loaded we call this change image function which is javascript and we also have a handle
create these both get call?
So, I'm going to go into this.
Exist opens up my...js.
Zoom in on this.
And, that so you guys can see it.
So, here's a handle creative and what the hell creative and does it every time a user creates
a new game and they click on a card...has to do something so it's going to flip so this functional
...the cards there's two cards flip spell-check if there's a match?
If there is a match lecture reload the game and football the
cards back there's not a match it flips them back and, that's just really the function that does the clicking and
accounting of if you've successfully...completed the game or not.
When you come down here you can see there's a flip image function really all does just foot images back and forth?
And, there's a change image so this is the partner game where.
We actually will take images and svqs randomized them so that
when you play new game they're not the same spot every time so we need to be able to changes images...change
...call we actually called get images and right now and get images we have all of images stored in the
sql client which I've installed already and you can see in my web dot com fake on
pointing to it so that's the game host things that...semi connections string which is a
sql client and this information that you get when you deploy that vm so...actually all my vm
...preloaded the...with some basic images.
And, this is the web...
So, this will actually go through and I'll say is our topic...later we'll have a topic right now is just
the basic game we're actually going to a post call...this is...comes...aspect of it.
Handling images actually put those images in the array that they're going to be when
they flip over and then the match the pattern build
...function that randomly chooses index zeroed matches index three and every time you
play game it rearranges indexes so it's a random game to add challenging make
...challenging there's a sleep for how long you wait before
you flip there's some reset game functions and everything else and here's kind of just...
So,...coming back to these ones quite frequently as we've all this game.
Right now it's going...the get image because that's actually dealing with...so the image
...if you come into it and...again.
You can see I have for the default game I've hard coded some text.
So, google xbox hello goodbye and their mapped to the actual images for each one of these
autumn so this is a six card game when they flip you get taxed, you know,
when you can image you want to matches to?
So, we are using sequels...vn which has the same images if the
connection that fails we fail back to these ones here's our cloud storage accounts on just initiating a
blob storage this is actually for chat later when we implement that.
...are dictionary the holds all the images for the game
...sql so they're actually key value...
And, then here's the actual message that is on our api site that is get image
That does is it passes in a content body from http message
...content body will have something...we empty so the first function says is an
empty yes it will be for the basic game because of no topics their soon will implement topics
no actually a topic that we're...actually parse over and actually use...being api...you get
...skip over that there's an if statement...through and says okay did the
...connection fail more or less if it did we're going to actually just choose
these default images and mappings up here if it didn't we're going to use.
On our image details which is actually are dictionary that stored
and refers to the...client on...in...
You can see the dictionary we'll use that later for making more difficult...actually going to
...things in the dictionary based someone people search for a topic.
Here's parse build that we do international chat and then you see there's some helper functions in here.
So, we've kind of walk through a large part this now we gotta get to the actual model
the model and here is going to be right here the image monitor zoom
and again you can see we have a db context...accessory...db for the
...string you can see here I also refer to in the web dot com vague and they're also gives us our
...our...of this table you see we're going to be
calling image details and rand-r key is going to be based on the text.
We have a class which defines with those image details
are another obvious things like what the images with the text is the image source like
...source the text location in the database so on so forth
...pretty obvious what's going on there so I think I've described everything
there is javascript file which I went through there's accounts...home controller so
...where you go to actually login on the website so we won't do that yet because that's authenticated you
controller is one that actually takes in all the calls from the home page.
So, you can see that there's.
Yes, so, this first...
dom actually going to be building an application and evolve into a more complex applications we
multi-user and I can take that application and actually build a resource provider
and sell in address store and I'll show you that whole process.
Yeah, so, there's a lot of lead up I'm trying to make it more fun and more realistic this
to show that you can actually use the marketplace itself to
take tons of services all...amusing about eight different services building a web application that's just fun for
anyone to play and then I'm going to provision user counts for people to come in log into play
this game that's kind of the story so that's kind of a nugget first there so thanks for the question.
Okay.
So, why do we build this puppy?
It should bill just fine.
And, I will actually...locally so...website yet actually want to
see run here publishing takes over longer than just doing on your local host.
And, I'm generally not claim to be the best developer so,...performance of this is not optimum this is just
for a demo you can see that have those dave's so
...showing...have a hello there's no login journalese of in hp dot
net site but I've replaced it so looks and feels like this here's images for the backs of
the card and you can see when I flip them there's good-bye hey I got was lucky beer.
...really lucky today you can see it's randomized changes rights...is now there.
Or I got one wrong that's good you.
Keep doing this and every time you do it does a...the page results again so we want to make this more interesting is actually one of
actually see myself get a score on play against other people...more challenging.
So, I will close this and I will actually
deploy this to the website we create before on the portal if you remember that.
Using visual studio all the id...their integrated fairly well
...publishing saying coming here and I can actually say I...to...website...you can see
...well if you can see it's my username that...the poorer with.
Will actually look up all my websites and ic memory friends demo...okay
...download all my publishing files which allows me to connect as your yes?
I will publish.
...after this built-in does all deployment
...papa website this actually live in an audience...go to...flip with the six cards.
Swan deploying that.
I'm going to start building the leader board part of the game.
And, I have a lot...bakes willing to do is I'm going up websites coming up now you can see it.
The club next-door.
Right so you can see this action memory with friends demo at adder websites
dot net anyone room
...go to this and it works the exact same way in the end-all have.
All...play.
But, we want to the leader board score.
And, lead aboard.
...the...that's against...and we need to add a new view to this that's
actually...to look and feel of the reward.
...to hear on-the-go index dot cs html.
I'm going to add this leader board right above...for all the cards.
You can see here that there's going to name...score...rank.
And, they will sort.
then it's actually called leader boards will have a label which is great.
And, I'm going to go into.
Javascript.
The...work with suppose to.
...we make sure that we update the score every time a new game is played.
So, you go down to get images or down to this functional reset
thing game which is right here we wrote the game measure every time you
...again that means games completed you update the score...user.
Everyone make sure that we actually...the scoreboard so when I'm playing a game
might may not be completed other people from the games might finish their games I want to see their score get updated.
I want to go down to change image.
...three seconds...milliseconds.
And, then I'm going to add functions for.
The polling...scoreboard...these functions real quick.
...magic and this is actually in the javascript...the controller's.
So, we have the do posts which is called every three seconds actually check the score.
...data...there are scores updated in the...sequel
...update scores called...just added when you...game.
The...table creates of this table score...score doesn't exist it goes through and creates
an sorts every time there's an issue...actually redo this.
And,...handle score which is.
What the function above called cc these are all ajax calls against these
...controller which means we prior to update...controller code now?
...we're going to account controller...reuse our models.
Which we do great and then we want to add this?
...actually handle that post call.
...oebps
it actually registers the user in the table upon registering for the system.
You can see the top here we actually are...art...
When we go to this page?
...down here though via natural register and after they successfully
...systems the correct e-mail password there's no duplicates...add them to our leader board.
We...controller.
This is the main page.
Where use the models that's great?
...here and uncommon this out so now every time I load some
...or on the web will actually asked authenticate myself.
I make sure now I'm passing in the model for the scoreboard before we weren't.
...index is just the home page.
And, then we need to actually have a push.
...for update score.
...this ad that.
Before the about.
So, the scoreboard is where the scoreboard and identity users added this is...to push
...happens so when I...post does that and here's update score which actual update the
scoreboard when someone does this so I'm just linking the...now and now we actually
have the model which is if you go in here.
We're going to add them scoreboard model.
Which is?
And, I'll walk you through that.
Scoreboard similar to what we have for the
image monitor we have a scoreboard we have a db context.
We have it creating the scoreboard
...here actually build and see what resolution issues we're having.
Don't have a model scoreboard alright so I forgot to add a file?
So, if I go into image monitor
...right there and add thatwe need to set the
...contacts in that controllers well or not model and...is...
So, the top we connector are sequel dvd we're going to store the scores
there as well as organist or the image details and scoreboard there and
...going to find actually what that object is here's object for the scoreboard.
Zoom out a little bit.
Ok, so, now we have a scoreboard you can see that each
...as user...a name and then we have modifier successor functions.
So, we should be are built this exceeded...awesome especially since the demo.
I'm going to build this and...so again I'm just...to local host all deploy the last one on
...on actual websites over can play.
And, what's going to do is...about your noticeable asked me to authenticate who I
am I'm already I already have test...in the system and I've been playing with this for the past few days so I'm in
the systems underscore login I'm not actually register.
See missive...calm.
Just before we came right here the same link and it was actually the card game but now it's having
...if you come to this and you don't have username you
just register you get write-in just provide an email...password.
And, then once a slowed...hello my name's my username has the game again and there's a
leader on the right.
Sometimes it doesn't work perfectly first-time so I have to refresh
every go so it's sort of it finally you can see I'm in the first rank with three
...nine points and everyone below me is the leader board so when I go to
...you can see a three hundred sixty nine points.
On a...game show that I'm actually going to get some more points.
...anyway that was.
So, that...doo-doo posts the
game flips over the scoreboard will actually updates hopefully.
If not you can see my score data increase no didn't...
...do of refresh again.
Enable come back to the scores here...start doing this at...slow right now on
my computer I could deploy this in a work the same will come back to this part.
So, close this...to debug are.
Now what we want to do is...make the game a
...more exciting or add more stuff to it again.
Going to go back and we're going to allow us to invite friends and we're going to...on the
bing search api to get new topics...get new images so again
add new code for asking the user for a topic.
You can see
...asking me zoom out a little bit says enter topic or
chooses seahawks...choose one by default there's an...type in the texts.
And, you see that we actually have an image first six twelve and sixteen tile game
this causes set tile function javascript so when you make sure
we updated javascript before we do that I want to add another dave for the e-mail
aspect of the game...that right after the table and here you can see challenger friends gives you text box
internet email that actually will send...mail we use...for that and behind-the-scenes.
...my javascript and here you can see we're now going to a topic.
So,...the...gs we actually do that change the image you see the
topic is...we're...ask user for topic they don't have to
...one but they do they'll actually call this function and start calling are being search dpx.
We...make sure that we set the tiles based on how many tile game they
want to play.
...at the end this is really just on hiding other dave's you can see there's one for six
...one for twelve there's one for sixteen.
This is are send email function...come to this...output in file now...revisited.
Again, they're all just based on...do a and http post.
Some controller and add some new references because we are doing is recalls.
Then we have this post which is sending the mail.
Out that.
Now at right after the last post we added.
Okay, so,...going to...as you can see.
Now we are...image monitor I apologize.
Tv context...that's actually the home controller...controller.
So, I'm having our times scene.
...image...image control we need to get
image the function talk about forward checks to see
images exists or not we now have content racially post message.
And, we'll check for that now...user types...topics say microsoft edge the new
browser no-go...here and I'll call are being search api.
And, that bing search api is in here which I head.
Into the marketing on by the being search api it gives you an api keys you-can call
...with that credential and passing any topic you want
so just you go to bing search you can type in something you can do through programmatic api
as well so here I'm calling the api which is
bing search I'm calling their news search.
Using micron...
As well as the api key they provide me.
And, I'll actually get the title I'll get a list of news results-based on-topic I do on a
plot the title for all of those at least sixteen because I'm
doing a sixteen card game potentially...title on
...the being search again this time notice I'm calling
being search composite images.
So,...image
...actually take the title the image in your...image and that's what's can use for the mapping.
And, you go through.
In a store that article database and when someone actually loads
...game...database and load...games based on image I was typed in?
Go back to...js.
And, that was the get images so that shortest...now announcer
calling being search we have sequel vm running was on adder website.
And, then we're going to do singer announce we actually...mail.
And, I will close this...we've done needs.
This...set tiles us when we went through.
Here's a send mail function...we do a post.
Many update are actual controller for this.
We are...forgot about...me.
Home controller we see we have a send mail so this is something can
...marketplace and purchase and it gives you an api key to construct a...to
...optional you from the subject lines here you can say we've invited to play
comp layer game we type in the website for this you can
see I'm eventually going to put to memory with friends demo...websites dot com and then I actually use
smt client for sigrid and I...the mail.
So, this all should build.
...build.
...now see the card game we'll see some new tips for
choosing a topic choosing the size of the game will see the leader board analysis...actually invite friends.
So, applications involved pretty quickly and the short on time we've been here.
And, again, it's just some...machine I've already log...apply recognize that did my
cookie's yep, now you can see there's new dev choose a topic.
You can choose six...sixteen for the same-size.
You can see now it's sorting the...
fine and below you can actually invite someone to play so I can invite myself.
Microsoft-dot-com.
And, invite...my email open...privacy very distracting during this but that will
send an email an email will eventually look like this.
You can format anywhere you want to see says the same message I
...there there's a link to the actual website...marketplace works pretty
seriously you can make a pretty verbose and singled also has analytics for...so if you're doing any kind of
...targeting of ads...tracking it's very useful.
So, the choose microsoft edge.
So, I heard a lot about that today...keep the six person game
or six card game because it becomes very difficult because it takes the title any of the match to
...sometimes they don't necessarily match perfectly two-c says
...edge browser logo pays homage to internet explore.
Nope,...another one so that will flip back over.
There is that's a match probably guessing
those are matches this one says...fifteen day one recap windows ten.
All right so rematch.
And, exception that's awesome.
So, I will act like that didn't happen and.
To put one more time.
...dynamic before we had...say google...xbox are beer after a few
games you gets very boring right so now we...using search and actually going and getting
...title and then going and image-based on the news title and now and actually try to
make a bigger game which is much more difficult this time I will say.
Windows ten.
Or twelve so you can see the games actually
increase in size negative sixteen as well gets bigger so grows.
This...to play and
...you can see it actually pulls in all...stuff you need.
To do this so it's pretty...
There's...my email so I just received email that I said earlier.
Just great.
Close my outlook.
And, now what we want to do is want to make...even more interesting by adding chat this will be international
shot so we're going to add chat too as well as making it called the bing translation...
And, to do this again...I start with our.
Going to go into our view which is index the html
...the very end of the game.
...be below the cards
...left the...you can see there's a comment section arts read-only is...actually all the scrolling
text will be...see you can choose if you want to go from english spanish or spanish...which
...spanish...trying to learn spanish right now...call javascript function which is post message.
So, we need to update the javascript site that's just say address to
actually have this within the change image will make sure that we again poll
...did for the scoreboard the...for chat.
And, go into here.
We're going to go to our change image function
...four seconds of course this could be two seconds one second just shows...at random.
We're...go and find our post message which is the original javascript function now...call internal function.
To do all the processing of the chat.
So, if I go back up this...for message.
...a covered all over.
And, this f for fudge.
What I do around here?
...and aryans it's good so, post message...internal post message
...again.
Is going to go and check what...what's another language it's going to do it
...a post message or controller that internal
...are being translation api to actually do the translations attacks
...post-it to the chat window here's where we handle the
comments this is actually popped in the comments make sure always focused on the bottom
here's the...function which does the same...above but it does it on a pulling function?
And, then we need to add to our controller.
...image controller you can see this is the
...calls message slash comments you can see that was right.
...send mail.
...is the right there.
So, that's the controller actually adding for this.
And, here's to get translated message.
Milwaukee through this so image controller.
Matter right...last http message...
That's...one...
Okay.
It does the response or gets message will actually go and check to see if
it's english or not it'll call get translate message which I'll go down
to the second and then it will display the text
in the chat window to be encircled by en?
Showing that equals eds you can see the transition
that chat so whether you speak english or spanish you should be able chat with someone else...the other language which is great.
...translate message if you come down and see it actually calls api so I went
...being translation and
I'm formatting the message based on this and I use my credentials actually call against the
being transition api...will spit out the actual response.
And, then we need to now since we added a new function to our controller we need to add some into our
...table.
For global the insects...right here so you can see we have a new.
Routing for this message...message last comments which is the function we just added.
And, I don't have that one open unless...been here.
...that's right that's the other one which is the api state forgetting images.
...to build I think I forgot somethin'.
Yes, I didn't
add the table entity which is the table for the actual.
Come down here and add that in.
Groups...I'm sort of fsix.
Hopefully this works...didn't see that there's a build errors.
When of deployed if it wasn't?
Going to recognize me now we should have...here.
None...deploy this...anyone else can go to this.
Website.
...actually login and compete.
So, that resorted chats and there I have a lot of chats and here already system
...all-time.
Ucl...zoom in a little bit more thought.
And, say how is everyone...post that.
You can seats right there that's...I have a...my code where that's still taking the last time stamp
one...practice some spanish ll got to comb a
For the chat need the bread.
I didn't see it actually populate.
it's it looks like I'm building that the chat wrong but you can see that it's actually translating
here when I typed in delgado coming
...actually said the caddy spread house everyone doin' is coma assay toto ellen
window that's kinda cool...then this still works the default images I can type it in
...is pretty cool but now let's see.
Let's actually deploy this.
Once we deploy we get into actually trying to publishes indoor as a marketplace.
So, comment here...publish.
Since very publish once the should be a little bit faster.
So, if you actually want to go to this website you can.
Will be a memory with friends demo dot as your websites dot net?
Consigned n play a game and you can see your score get updated.
...ft dot com.
Pe a ss wr d one-two-three.
So, if you guys are going to this...you guys actually chat...here and see that it's actually working with everyone
audience so again it's memory with friends demo dot as your websites dot net.
...slow to load
...priors that by an e zero website I typed in hello.
Just recently.
Say is there any one else in here with me.
...login soon...
...do this I can switch over and I'll start talking more about how to actually become a...and asher marketplace.
Sony spanish.
Shares...
Anyway,...move on.
Go back to my dec...you come back to this again so I can actually show you how you
can build resource provided actually provision through that your marketplace and sawyer services so,
why would you wanna-be seller well obviously discover ability there's hundreds of thousands
...users we both we sell the web direct result
...indirect and then we also support now yeah, indirect which is the reseller
model so people can actually go out so services very global market?
Building again we take care of all doing...payments from those customers who purchaser services we give you
payout for that we had all the legal and tax for-you at least in most of the regions.
...service...you can manage all your offerings you can have more than one offering you can do on of
gm a web app you can do it on many things so there's a huge service management
...for you to do this and I'll show you that today and then...confounding...the
...factors microsoft sales is now incentivizing to go out so
...service with isv and people around the world
...incentivize with money so they actually have accelerator where if
they sell services from the marketplace they get more and more incentives and more and more money to
increase their paycheck so you have this huge microsoft workforce behind you could be one
person cosine your service and your instantly go to market is huge it's global you
have a sales force you have a technical foresee of building back-end so,
it's really good reason to be a seller...off-the-floor if you're just trying to get that global reach?
The becoming a microsoft measure market partner one is apply
the ada and the slash so your service
...the ntwo you actually...tells by your company tells by your service tells about what you want
to do work with you there are as a certified program
will certify you both make sure your real company make sure that you have a great service your great asher
fit to help you with how you want to build your customers all kinds of stuff and
then you can integrate and that's...the demo going to show you and finally you...your service.
So, the next show-and-tell is going...publishing poorer which is as a publisher you go in and upload all your
metadata for offerings that's the marketing stuff...where you choose your
billing for that it's very update the technical limit are technical part
of your service it's where you have icons and images on anything you...to see in
a marketplace to create a resource provider it takes about one to two minutes which is great.
...to put all together...see in our stage environment that this web
...game is actually now going to be in...stage environment all within an hour
...built and app and put in the store so I will see it looks like some
people got in media jag cool thank you for playing.
So, I will minimize all these windows and
...go to the publishing portal now publishing portal like it says it's
define with...name...where publisher goes to publisher offers and, we will go to.
Thank you so much.
Going-to sign in using tessa can we have.
Soweto actually publish...offer and...marketplace.
I'm just going...in staging because usually want to stated before you go to productions...where you can tested.
Yes, please sign-out.
...will be aligned by the left side which is all your
workloads so you can see if I was a real publisher I would have eleven application services...selling I have five
...sign a data service...a promotional offers for your offerings and,
then this is where you actually registers publisher so has your company entity has
...is...payout that kind of stuff so for the memory game.
...friends I created one agency.
Yeah, so, at the end they'll been ak link rel share it's actually link to
our certified program which is where you go and apply to actually talk with our
...as a certified team from they'll help you go through this portal as well as learn how
to the resource provider stuff learn how to integrate your products and things like that.
Now your own store it's selling your services through rone
store.
You want to not have your own story...the hard way...to have one...store people can search for you and
they're familiar with it so having that familiarity that consistency having a
third-party next first party and they look the same is advantageous for non microsoft folks so,
you want to go through...this portal actually does all the magic behind the back-end and then
put your package out in front of everyone.
it's really whatever you put into is what you get out of its you could...very quick amount of time or you could
stage...or wait for splash so it's really what you want to get out of it but
...this portion for you can define the plans you have your offering right now...kind of a free one so
...sign up you can set to have a promotion...additional plans.
You can have meters sort negative point where you can actually bill for...specific type of meter so this
is like overs billings you pay for u then we have marketing.
Is...where you give your offering a title you give it a summary I've given a description
this is all boiler plate just kind of fake dummy data
uci have this brain lift some weights because it's brain our
it's memory game so it's just a fun game and, I want to make it obvious that
wasn't a real offer then you have links so here I'm calling all the services that I did there's some that I didn't actually
list of being search as...websites you can put any links...here
...useful for your customers integrate to watch
demo videos to reference other collateral all the marketing
...want-to thing with links?
You sample images which is I'm showing you actually what the game looks like
to the users they can see before they actually provision and do it you can add multiple images you give descriptions your
plans so it's a free one on the play invite your friends?
Hons redefine...I don't have any...can do that you have a privacy policy and you
have terms of use here user...is from different putting in pricing you can actually
price per region you see for the all the eighty-six regions we have and here you can
...differently or you can set the price for one region...for us I did here
...auto price for all the other regions and we add new ones that are prices for those too so,
it's very useful and you can imagine the global reach.
Then supports this engineering context is to be your actual team that
we've contact there's an issue cusses...is what the customers...contact they experience
...issue categories so we actually...offering into the certain parts of
the marketplace so your question sir where you want to...up in the marketplace you get five options up to five?
And, the resource provider so this is the part where we want to
actually provision resource so we have asher and the marketplace
...back-end orchestrate and then your services over here and somehow we need to connected to so we stampa we call
...rp or resource provider...does...provisioning for your service so that's
when someone creates an account it creates an account using rp when I deleted they deleted when I want to manage it
...all as manager operations all that's all through desiccated we have on visual studio and we're
growing at other languages too so I think...I have no js or other languages love to get feedback
and languages that you guys might be interested in implementing...not all...csharp in visual studio
fans you plug-in endpoint here when you actually build it so let's switch over and actually build one.
...easy it is.
So, the coming here...file new project.
And, this is something my boss hasn't even seen yet so you guys is the hot off the press.
Which is great?
And, I'm going to search for resource.
...should pop-up as...resource?
...marketplace resource provider.
Going to give it a name.
And, I'm actually...a call it.
...to call...call it's memory game.
...pi-zero one share that sounds great.
Right and then we have some stuff that we have to give it this is stuff that will walk you through when you actually go through the on
...process.
name space sets memory name space we memory main spaces slash memory game.
You need to storage account is actually store usage another important information for your
service that way we know-how to build on your behalf and you give it to a
...most likely updating it these first two options are really just
a way for us identify what your services how to contact rp and things like that...okay.
It's a fairly it's not a significant large file but, we abstract a lot of
agile concepts here we except all the technical stuff and really all you have to do is can one file.
So, what's going on.
Unrecognized escape sequence.
Apologize...I...the wrong button.
So, maybe that's requirements may takes ten.
There.
...the same name.
Our cost memory can.
This...dance club next-door.
Awesome noted in.
Anyway, so, you do is you coming here and
there's all the functions for provisioning the provisioning and managing...service zoom in.
Rodeo you beer perfect so, you can see that I have.
Marketplace request...I'm provision resourcewhich will actually go through and I'll have a way for
...provision?
Keys for folks such as an api key here this is set up for like a storage
structure.
That has service properties you can see their specific ports are endpoints on replace
...this stuff.
...you come down to the provisions is actually remove assist a user from the system.
...resource so anything you want...service like a status
and api key or if you want to do something related to that service that specific that service you do
through that function this all communicates with our back-end and your service.
You can regenerate all your keys sort of say you have a password and...breached you
can reset it get communication preferences this is something so you can communicate you
want to transaction basis as well as a promotional basis you can set what...email is
the first-time last same if they want to be infer promotional communications ...
updating this communication preferences and list goes on...for this demo
...update the provisioning.
The provisioning everyone gets to
...their user management is however they
...you...again so...provision someone
...a database...should give them the key see of the mappings that way you can find them
...delete if you want you can update them...sequel and I'm actually in a store that using hash.
This is also...drive you to I don't recommend you do this
...require much more secure way to do it...by a different way that you want to do it.
Well, the sequel connection here which is great.
And, then.
Within the actual provisioning function on a provision a user.
Put the current provision users you can see here I'm opening the...connection
...them...into a time stamp to make it is unique as possible I'm doing it at
hatcher marketplace dot com so this is actually...use assign into the memory game website they're going to be
they're...is password so it's nothing secure for now I'm going to store that using
hash password function that on from the next...rate now.
So, I'll actually open up the connection are right there username and password and
dragging stuff into the sequel connection now close an update the dictionary
and then I will show them that I'm going to give them their keys once they.
...added the system.
You see here.
I'm going to replace the storage related information and replace it with us.
The username password...website.
The game.
So, now they have a username a password and a link when they go into their manager for the resource of
...they can click on the keys they'll see their username or password in the key.
And, for the provisioning I really do the complete opposite of all that I open up
the sequel database and I delete the user and then I...
I will build this.
Get all...is doing is just database connections and adding and using users
so it's pretty simple so, somewhere in here when you're doing a provisioning
...calling your api is on your
service actual revision people or to give them access keys and things like that.
So, that builds and I will deploy this.
Actually I want to locally I can actually put to a website.
Now...hoses rp...one to many places around the world depending on how you do your traffic management or
...balancing what happens we have ...resource manager which is like the god
resource provider it does all provision someone purchases something in knows that your resource provider
exists errol make calls to your resource providers authenticated calls and then from here this is how it
plugs into your so we have a threat model which is only one entry point
that's arm and all the communication through that through this rp?
And, so.
I can actually deploy this.
...I publish...be at a...overtime bummer.
...to new website was called.
Memory...p
zero one large choose west us and our create.
While that's loading.
The publishing poorly you can go to publish neck and it pushes staging.
This allows me to set the sub ideas are the people who can actually test in
ui so we actually will vet who they are and only services for those testers.
Already added that lists.
Okay, and, I'm going to log...
So, we are staging portal.
Looks and feels the same way with some slight differences.
You can see that the are...was provision I believe.
...publish.
Multitasking now...see it's df dot one cloud badger test
...are preponderance is where you can test the only
...services that you're testing for no one else...this
...do all it's not the best environment...slower but it's a great way to test before you actually go
to production and production related testing production as well as multiple stages producing something so,
this is saying that rp actually provision which is great.
You can see it's...development node
...actually url...here that lets me do optimizations to see more debug information.
Thank you for waiting I ran over time.
Wasn't expecting some of the delays.
...in fact...reload this.
...pretty good.
Through these shows where everything comes to fruition I guess second-story answer questions why this is loading but it will eventually load.
It's a special command actually on hides the extension so in
...similar to...rp there's a ui aspect which is your extension
for your service is hosted similar like with arm and,
it talks to both are you why as well as a talks the rp and
right now it's hidden in the environment and I'm on hiding it so that shows.
To the memory.
...down here is a little guy with the brainless in the
...sixty nine...offering the marketplace has all the same stuff as a
resource that is memory game...the funky image it's called memory friends shows image
...had before.
...the links but there are links and here...and I can actually create this...created some already.
Just for times...
Inherits resource...blade...actually click on the keys here you see the
username the password...stuff up and rp
...website and actually plug this in actually play the game.
So, since we are way over time I'm going to switch back over and I can answer questions afterwards I'll make...I
...some calls the action.
...show-and-tell...so sign up.
So, this is a...dot microsoft sign up free trial so if you don't have asher haven't used before want
...try it is a link to actually go get your free trial...I think two hundred...credits you go
...some services build a cool service to for free have fun you can you can copy this if
you want to just go...and get dirty, you know, reach out will be here all week ...look
...talking that you were still in the room...ada and...slash
cellular service this actually goes to our econ page which has the actual certified
and finally come medius we have a booth out here this is only sixty-minutes we...a lot more information for
...can answer direct questions so, that...running over time?
...show you...building application
and actually each selling application the marketplace please evaluate the session if you could.
I believe the cure codes out there as well.
And, then that's it thanks so much.
Thank you.